David Valls Lanàquera

Data Scientist

Meguro 4-7-9-102, Meguro-ku **Tokyo**, Japan

080-7793-6892 dvallslanaquera@gmail.com



Data Scientist with 5 years of experience and strong statistical background. Triple Master's Degree in applied statistics with R, Python and SQL and Business Intelligence and originally working in the neuroscience field as a biostatistician. Currently working in Japan with a working visa

Experience

Fujitsu CSL / Data Scientist

Aug 2018 - Present, Tokyo, Japan

- ➤ Data analyst for the Google Cloud Support project (~90 members).
- > Responsible for the customer volume forecast to fit agent skills to the demand and avoid customer attrition.
- > Real time dashboards created on Tableau, Google Data Studio and Plx using automated SQL pipelines based on KPIs and target accomplishment.
- ➤ Classification techniques used to analyse and improve workforce skill pool (k-means, GMM, DIANA and AGNES dendrograms).
- ➤ Wordcloud and sentiment analysis to identify customer's needs and pain points.

Institut Guttmann / Research Fellow (Statistician)

November 2015 - Sep 2017

- ➤ Laboratory specialized in spinal cord injury, working with 30 years of medical records.
- > A/B testing process created from scratch (randomization strategy election, block variables setting and experiment designment).
- Created advanced data visualizations to communicate research findings (heatmaps, tanglegrams, lollipop charts, etc.).
- > Robust and non-parametric statistics to fit small scale data.

Education

Rey Juan Carlos University / Applied Statistics with R Software MA

2017 - 2018

Supervised and unsupervised techniques using R and SQL with all the statistical foundations required for each technique. Robust statistics and non-parametric techniques included.

European Business School of Barcelona / Big Data and Business Intelligence MA

2018 - 2019

Knowledge deepened in fields related to Big Data like marketing plan designing, SEO positioning or KPI selection methodology.

Autonomous University of Barcelona / Neurorehabilitation in Spinal Cord Injury pre-PhD program

2015 - 2017

2 years pre-doctoral master's degree using R and SPSS in one of the most prestigious laboratories of Europe in Spinal Cord Injury.

University of Valencia / Neuropsychology

2009-2014

Languages

Japanese: proficiency (Noken 1 obtained in 2017)

English: advanced
Spanish: native
Catalan: native

Italian: intermediate

Other links

Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/david-valls
Twitter: https://twitter.com/Standby-00

Github portfolio: https://dvallslanaquera.github.io/dvalls/xgboost.html